Arjun Ankathatti Chandrashekara

arjun.ankathatti@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/acarjungowda | +1 (573) 639-3762

SUMMARY

Full stack software developer close to 4 years of industrial experience in Design, Development, and Implementation of Enterprise Web Application using **J2EE** Framework and Object-oriented programming. Excellent Technical, Analytical, Problem Solving skills, strict attention to detail and ability to work independently, work within a team environment.

EDUCATION

University of Missouri

Columbia, Missouri

Master of Science in Computer Science, GPA 3.8

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant, Networking and Multimedia lab, University of Missouri

August 2016 - Present

Graduation: December 2018

Multi-Cloud Resource Recommender

- Design and development of web application using Struts2 and Tiles framework
- Coded JDBC calls in the DAO classes to access the Oracle database tables
- Worked with 3rd party API's such as Amazon AWS Java SDK
- Published paper "Recommending Resources to Cloud Applications based on Custom Templates Composition" in the ACM Computing Frontiers Conference, 2017

CyNeuro.org – Neuroscience Gateway

- Designed and developed the gateway portal using PHP Laravel framework, AngularJS, Bootstrap4
- Embeddable Chatbot widget on the portal using JavaScript and JQuery
- Created RESTful API endpoints using Python and FLASK micro framework
- Managing Linux/Unix application servers and basic system administration

Database Programmer Analyst, MU Division of IT, Columbia, Missouri

January 2017 - June 2017

- Designed and developed .NET based solution using C#, ASP.Net, ASP.NET MVC
- Built utility class libraries and created product critical stored procedure in SQL Server
- Developed responsive web UI using Bootstrap, CSS which increased website usability by 30%

System Engineer, Infosys, Bangalore, India

October 2014 - July 2016

- Implemented business logic in service layer classes and created model classes
- Developed UI in Spring MVC framework using JSP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery
- Proposed Pentaho Spoon ETL tool for data migration and transformation, which saved 60% of the effort and time
- Shared knowledge of tools and techniques with the wider team, both developers and non-developers

PROJECTS

Budget – Expense Manger

- Developed reusable user interface components and implemented them with Redux
- Compiler JSX with babel presets, bundled the modules with web pack, and tested the apps with Jest
- Setup authentication, user accounts, routing, form validation and configured the DB storage

Online tic-tac-toe game

- Real-time two-way communication between client and server using Socket.IO and Node.js
- DOM manipulation to update game state using JQuery based on the events triggered by the Server
- Implemented a game room concept which enables users to join the game based on unique game ID

Self-learning Algorithm to play Checkers

- Built min-max tree using alpha-beta pruning to identify the best possible move
- Fully connected multi-layer perceptron was used as the heuristic function
- Tournament selection to determine the successful game playing strategies

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

: Java, Python

Web & scripting

: HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, CSS, AJAX, JSON

Frameworks & Libraries

: Struts2, Flask, React.js, node.js

Database

: SQL Server, Oracle 11g, MySQL

Software Tools and others

: Git, SVN, Gulp, Sublime, Eclipse

AWS

: EC2, Lambda, RDS, ELB, IAM, S3, CloudWatch